hdwallpaperspot.com 2014-02-12

# Privacy Policy | hdwallpaperspot.com

Hdwallpaperspot.com clearly honors the privacy and security of its valuable visitors. Every visitor’s confidentiality is secured through a methodical and complete privacy policy. Hdwallpaperspot clearly defines the information it collects from its visitors, and how the information is used.

Once the amount of collected information is clearly stated, the user feels more secure and at ease when browsing the website. Internet browsing is not free of spam and scams, thus at hdwallpaperspot we collect only the relevant personal information of a user. This information is used to enhance the visitor’s experience at the website. The visitor’s personal information is safeguarded and not given to any third parties on hdwallpaperspot.

The following types of information are stored by the website.

**Log Files**

The website stores any data given in the log files of the user. This is a common practice carried out by most web pages on the World Wide Web. A user’s log file information on hdwallpaperspot stores the IP (Internet Protocol) address, the ISP name, the time the website was visited, the information of pages visited and the browser used (Safari, Internet Explorer etc.).

**Cookies and Web Beacons**

Once a visitor logs in to hdwallpaperspot, the website strives to provide him/her with a unique browsing experience. To ensure that the advertisements etc. viewed by a user are of related interest, the web site stores cookies. These cookies stock up a visitor’s personal preferences and browsing information.

Cookies are also responsible for giving the users many privileges on the website. Advertisements take the help of a user’s cookies to display ads of a user’s interest. Advertisers also use web beacons for the same purposes. It extracts information about a user’s browser, plug in details, ISP and IP address.

Google also provides the DART cookies technology, which can help advertisements relating your interests reach you. However, as a visitor hdwallpaperspot gives you full control and you can opt out of this service at any time.

If you do not approve of the retrieval of personal information, you can opt out of it by installing any antivirus services. This will fulfill your privacy measures but it might also limit your usability of the website. This is because certain features require cookies to function.

**Third Party Advertisers**

Hdwallpaperspot employs third party advertisers to improve the browsing experience. Third party advertisers use algorithms to provide our visitors with ads of their interest. Therefore to carry out this task, third party advertisers are given your personal information, so the algorithms can efficiently figure out the best ads for you.

Any personal information like the visitor’s name, address, contact information etc. is not handed over to the third party advertisers.

Once again, Hdwallpaperspot allows you to opt out of this service as well. We work to make your browsing experience safe, secure and enjoyable – wishing you protected and fruitful browsing!
